Brand Strategist → Curriculum vitae

Louis ten Kate

SENIOR BRAND STRATEGIST

CONTACT

+44 [0] 7805 332 201 louis@signsandsignifiers.com signsandsignifiers.com

Author

Louis ten Kate

Private & Confidentia

Experience [Short form]

Employment

Senior Brand Strategist

→ Signs & Signifiers · London · Freelance

APR 2023 — PRESENT · 6 MOS

Senior Brand Manager

→ RHEON Labs · London · Full time AUG 2021 — APR 2023 · 1 YR 9 MOS

AGENCY CLIENTS

Rapha, Harley-Davidson, Adidas

Senior Brand Specialist

→ FreshBritain · London · Full time

JAN 2018 — JUL 2021 · 4 YRS 5 MOS

AGENCY CLIENTS

Arquus, Bear Grylls, Caroline Groves, Concord Resources, Rheon Labs, Roxor Group, Montane, Higher Ground

Senior Brand Designer & Creative Strategist

→ Freelance · London · Full time OCT 2015 — SEP 2017 · 2 YRS

AGENCIES

Aeron, Bisqit (H+K), Brand Brewery, ForPeople, TwelthMan, Idea is Everything, Industry Branding, Saatchi & Saatchi

AGENCY CLIENTS

AkzoNobel, BNY Mellon, BMW, CBD Bank, Clarity PR, DHL, EuroLeague, Gain Capital, Gardens Montessori, Hau Wei, Holiday Inn, HSBC, Samsung, Lenovo, Motorola

Education & Certification

w

Marketing Week

→ mMBA: Marketing



University for the Creative Arts

→ BA: DSA | Majoring in semiotics within advertising 1st Class Honours



IDEO U

- → Designing Strategy
- → Designing a business
- → Human centred service design
- → Business Innovation



42 Courses

- \rightarrow Innovation
- → Behavioural economics
- → Applied behavioural science
- → Behavioural science for effective messaging



Futurelearn

- → Anthropology: Understanding societies and cultures
- → Product management essentials
- → Digital marketing analytics & measurement
- → Business strategy



Brand Strategy Academy

→ Brand strategy



Lego Serious Play

→ Workshop Facilitator [pending]

Profile

OVERVIEW

Full stack brand strategist & qualified marketer* with over 10 years commercial experience working in-house, agency-side and on the tactical front line.

My unique background allows me to think holistically about brand building and avoid the [unnecessarily] common breakdown between strategy and tactics.

PHILOSOPHY ON BRAND

I define brand as 'a system of meaning around a given entity'. A good brand strategy therefore, is the informed design of that system — be it for a place, product or PLC. A clear brand strategy clarifies the entities ambition and accelerates the path to growth.

SKILLS

- Brand & product positioning
- Proposition development
- Messaging hierarchy
- Contextual analysis
- Brand architecture
- Semiotic analysis
- Value proposition
- Brand story
- Naming
- UX/CX
- EVP

Experience [Long form]

Employment

SENIOR BRAND STRATEGIST

→ Signs & Signifiers · London · Freelance

SENIOR BRAND MANAGER

→ RHEON Labs · London · Full time

RHEON is a B2B technology company that has developed an ultra-high energy absorbing super-polymer.

I came in-house to develop the brand-building and positioning strategy. Within the space of a year I transforming the company's positioning from a generic blue protective rubber manufacturer — to an exciting new space-age technology firm.

- Spearheaded the internal brand 'Culture programme' and EVP
- Led all comms: brand and performance marketing campaigns: including budget planning, staff hiring and launch campaign creative narratives. Which included product collaborations with Harley-Davidson, Rapha and Adidas
- Conducted thorough competitive analysis of related product categories, providing valuable industry insights to informed future product marketing activities campaigns and buyer segmentation
- Managing Brand messaging across the full marketing mix including messaging hierarchy and TOV
- Developed online and offline CX/UX principles
- Facilitated C-Suite leadership workshops
- Responsible for brand measurement, tracking and copyright management

SENIOR BRAND SPECIALIST

→ FreshBritain · London · Full time JAN 2018 - JUL 2021 · 4 YRS 5 MOS

FreshBritain is a brand design agency and brand strategy consultancy. Leveraging emotional brand connection to transform company performance. [Using brand archetypes... ahem]

I brought rigour and structure to the companies existing branding process — which was previously based on an advertising creative delivery model.

- Independently numerous rebrand projects including; a luxury footwear atelier, a b2b bathrooms manufacturer, a british personal fitness icon and a commodities trading firm
- Spearheaded two of the companies largest most complex rebrand projects including; Renault Trucks Defense's transformation to Arguus. And the simultaneous rebrand of five sub brands belonging to the American Montessori network Higher Ground... In six weeks.
- Wrote brand film treatments, manifestos and narratives. including the winning concept for Montanes 2021 'Never stood still' product campaign film
- Stood as the agencies point man for web design projects, leading the UX and UI design of three web based projects

Experience [Long form]

Employment

SENIOR BRAND DESIGNER & CREATIVE STRATEGIST

→ Freelance · London · Full time OCT 2015 - SEP 2017 · 2 YRS

I worked across London at a number of high [and low] profile agencies within a hybrid capacity.

SECTORS SERVED

Arts & Culture / Technology / Banking & Finance / Sport / Education / Hospitality & Leisure / Outdoor & Adventure / Manufacturing & Materials / Professional Services

SERVICES PROVIDED

- Design & Art Direction
- Brand identity design
- Web design: UI/UX
- Service design

CONTENT CREATOR

→ Stylus · London · Full time JUN 2012 - OCT 2015 · 3 YRS 5 MOS

Stylus is the expert's source for trends and insights. Existing to help connect ideas and uncover possibilities that help businesses navigate change and look beyond the present to make informed decisions for a complex future.

Arriving at the early stages of the then startup, I helped build the marketing teams value offer, from video content creation to innovation workshop design and building consumer trend reports

Selected clients





































Selected case studies [On request]



Launching a new tech start up into space



Building a practical design system for a montessori network thats on the up



Crafting an enchantmenting story for luxury souls



Forging a new warrior for a new era of defense



Re-connecting with the true meaning of adventure to run lean again



Making business problems great again

Like what you see? Want to know more? Give me a shout.

louis@signsandsignifiers.com 44 [0] 7805 332 201